Finding Aid for William Albright Papers 1962-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Programs
  Albright tried to obtain copies of the programs from every performance by him, or of his works. These are retained in the series Programs (3.5 linear feet). The bulk of the programs are arranged chronologically; there are also four folders arranged geographically. The series also contains two folders of program notes arranged by song title, though more program notes are to be found among the programs themselves.
  - 1960-1965 (Box 5)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 5)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - 1970-1980, 11 folders (Box 5)
    (1970 folder includes a calendar of performances)
  - 1981, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 1982-1984, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - 1985, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 1986, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 1987, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 1988, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 1989, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - 1990, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - 1991, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 1992, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - 1993, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - 1994, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - 1995, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - 1996, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - 1997-1998, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Undated (Box 7)
  - Program Notes
    - Alphabetical by song title undated (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous undated (Box 8)
  - Austria and Germany 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Europe
    - 1976-1979 (Box 8)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Kiev 1995-1996 (Box 8)
- Professional Files
  The Professional Files series documents some of Albright's professional activities, including public lectures, participation in professional organizations, and publicity and reviews of his compositions, performances and recordings.
  The lectures are divided into "Lectures for the road," and Albright's opaque classifications "A" and "B."
  Some of the organizations with which Albright was professionally involved, and on which he kept files, are the American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), the First Unitarian Universalist Church of Ann Arbor, Great Lakes Performing Artist Associates, and Karen McFarlane Artists, Inc.
  The file titled Papers contains one paper by Albright, and ten by other authors about Albright. The researcher interested in papers about Albright should also consult the Reviews file in this series, as well as the files of Albright's individual works in the Scores series, where papers about a specific work are located.
  The Publicity files include correspondence and publicity flyers. The Reviews contains clippings arranged into composition, performance, publication and recording reviews.
  - Cacioppo, George (memorial fund) 1984-1987 (Box 8)
  - Grants 1978-1990 (Box 8)
  - Lectures
    - "A"
      - The Genesis of "A Song to David", undated (Box 8)
      - Gymphony, undated (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous 1985-1986, undated (Box 8)
      - Ragtime and All That Jazz (in German), undated (Box 8)
      - The Spirit of American Rhythm, undated (Box 8)
      - Uber den Geist des Amerikanische Rhythmus, 1981 (Box 8)
    - "B"
      - Bach and Symbolism, undated (Box 8)
      - Inside New Music--Lectures I-III, undated (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous undated (Box 8)
      - Musical Time in Two Cultures, undated (Box 8)
      - [Music and the '70's] circa 1980 (Box 8)
      - The New Organ Music, undated (Box 8)
      - Organ as Spiritual and Religious Force, undated (Box 8)
      - Organbook I and II, undated (Box 8)
      - Organbook III, undated (Box 8)
      - [Patronage and music] undated (Box 8)
      - [Ragtime] (in French) undated (Box 8)
      - Religious Music, undated (Box 8)
      - Music of the '90's: Media, Style and Direction, 1990 (Box 8)
      - Sacred Music in the USA (paper for the conference Musica Sacranella Societa Actuale, l'Abbazza Fossanova), undated (Box 8)
    - Lectures for the road
      - Church Music that Doesn't Sound Like Church Music, 1994 (Box 8)
      - Four Expressions (two versions), 1990, 1993 (Box 8)
      - New Textures for Organ or Organ Music that Doesn't Sound Like Organ Music, 1989-1997 (dated six times) (Box 8)
      - Sphaera ("Sphere"), undated (Box 8)
      - The Spirit of American Rhythm or What is American Music or The Vitality of American Rhythm/Music, undated (Box 8)
      - Where Do Compositions Come From? (for the Rotary Club), 1996 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous
      - "M" Songs--A Sampling of Michigan Songs from 1865-1920, undated (Box 8)
    - Michigan Journalism Fellows (University of Michigan)--Humanities Seminar 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Organizations
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP) 1967-1998, 3 folders (Box 8)
      (includes royalty statements)
    - Composers Recordings Inc. (CRI) 1990-1995 (Box 8)
    - First Unitarian Universalist Church of Ann Arbor
      - Church Programs--Special Music 1970-1985 (Box 8)
      - Music Director File 1972-1985 (Box 8)
      - Publicity 1985-1998, undated (Box 8)
      - Unitarian Universalist Musicians Network 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - Great Lakes Arts Alliance--Meet the Composer 1982-1987 (Box 8)
      (includes correspondence and ballots)
    - Great Lakes Performing Artist Associates 1987-1995 (Box 8)
    - Karen McFarlane Artists, Inc. (originally Murtagh/McFarlane Artists Management) 1981-1997 (Box 8)
    - Musical Heritage/Musicmasters 1980-1993 (Box 8)
    - National Endowment for the Arts 1976-1981 (Box 8)
      (includes application and correspondence)
  - Papers
    - Papers by W.A
      - Is There an American Music? or The Spirit of American Music, undated (Box 8)
    - Papers about W.A
      - An Analysis of William Albright's Jig for the Feet (Totentanz), by James H. Wagner 1995 (Box 9)
        (includes correspondence)
      - Cambridge Companion to the Organ--North America, by Douglas Reed, 1996 (Box 9)
      - Compositional Approaches to Tradition and William Albright's Clarinet Quintet, by Jennifer DeLapp, 1993 (Box 9)
      - The Compositional Style of William Albright, by James Perone, undated (Box 9)
      - [Five Chromatic Dances], by Steve Larson, undated (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous circa 1975-1991 (Box 9)
      - " 1732 In memoriam Johannes Albrecht by William Albright," 1993 (Box 9)
        In Interpretive Suggestions for Selected Czech, Swedish, and American Secular Organ Works Published 1977-1988, by Dorma Earl Holt (Arizona State University dissertation; includes correspondence)
      - Texture, Heterophony, and Pitch-Cell Treatment in the Compositions of William Albright, by James Perone, undated (Box 9)
      - Ways of Listening, by Ira Arthur Greenberg, 1977 (Box 9)
      - William Albright: Organ Music of the '80's, by Douglas Reed, undated (Box 9)
  - Performances (correspondence) 1981-1998 (Box 9)
  - Publicity
    - Correspondence 1990-1998 (Box 9)
    - Flyers undated (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous 1978-1997, undated (Box 9)
  - Reviews
    The Reviews sub-series contains clippings arranged into composition, performance, publication and recording reviews.
    - Composition Reviews 1962-1998, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Performance Reviews 1966-1998 (Box 9)
    - Peters Publication Reviews 1967-1996 (Box 9)
    - Recording Reviews 1971-1995, undated (Box 9)
- School of Music
  The School of Music series (.75 linear feet) contains files relating to Albright's career at the University of Michigan. It includes some administrative files from the Composition Department, syllabi and lecture notes from classes he taught, and a few dissertations by his students.
  - Career
    - Contests 1992-1998 (Box 9)
    - University of California, Santa Barbara 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - University of Michigan
      - Faculty Activities 1970-1998 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous 1972-1998 (Box 9)
  - Composition Department
    - Administration
      - 1974-1984 (Box 9)
      - 1987-1990 (Box 9)
      - 1990-1992 (Box 9)
      - 1992-1998 (Box 9)
    - Admissions 1995-1998 (Box 9)
    - Classes
      - Composition 221 1970-1989, undated (Box 9)
      - Composition 222 undated (Box 9)
      - Composition 421/422 1989-1993, undated (Box 9)
      - Composition 515 (Introduction to Electronic Music) 1970, undated (Box 9)
    - Computer Workstations 1990-1993 (Box 9)
    - Roger Johnson's Anthology, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Report on Peer Departments Throughout U.S., 1977 (Box 9)
  - Performances
    - Contemporary Directions Ensemble 1973-1997 (Box 9)
    - Contemporary Music Festival 1970-1975 (Box 9)
    - Midwest Composers Symposium 1980-1989 (Box 9)
  - Students
    - Dissertations
      - Analysis and Perception in Ligeti's Horn Trio, by Pierre D. Jalbert, undated (Box 10)
      - Dream Realized/Nightmare Resolved: A Dissertation Proposal, by William C. Banfield (Box 10)
      - Harmonic Behavior in "The Rite of Spring," by Curt Cacioppo, undated (Box 10)
      - The Notational and Compositional Procedures of the Unmeasured Preludes of Nicolas Lebegue, by Bonnie Choi, 1993 (Box 10)
      - Pluralism of Theatrical Genre and Musical Style in Henze's "We Come to the River," by Robert Hatten (Box 10)
      - The Role of Expression in Musical Understanding, by Robert Hatten, circa 1984 (Box 10)
      - Undulating Michigamme (abstract and progress report), by Sever Tipei, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Recommendations 1984, 1992-1998 (Box 10)
    - Student Work 1985-1995, undated (Box 10)
      (includes some comments from W.A.)
- The Magic City
  The Magic City (.25 linear feet) is an unfinished opera--set amid the 1893 Chicago World's Fair--that Albright planned for at least sixteen years with George Garrett, who helped write (or wrote) the libretto. The series contains files of Albright's notes, research materials and correspondence relating to work on the opera, as well as drafts of the libretto. In 1993 the University of Michigan Museum of Art organized an exhibition, "The Fair View: Alternative Visions of the World's Colombian Exposition," for which Albright gave a lecture/concert about music at the fair, and about the progress of The Magic City. A script of the lecture and correspondence pertaining to the exhibition can be found in this series. The series contains little musical material.
  - Correspondence and Notes 1980-1993 (Box 10)
  - Grant Application Materials 1980-1993 (Box 10)
  - Lecture, "Music at the Fair: From Ragtime to the Classics," 1993 (Box 10)
  - Manuscripts 1980-1988 (Box 10)
  - Research Materials 1972-1992 (Box 10)
- Scores
  The heart of the Albright collection is the series Scores (47 oversize boxes), which title refers to the broader definition of the word that includes any written version of a musical work, including parts and sketches.
  - William Albright Scores
    In the sub-series William Albright Scores, the researcher will find a file for each of Albright's works containing some or all of the following versions: notes, sketches, manuscripts, annotated reproductions of manuscripts, and printed scores. The existing versions are parenthetically indicated following the instrumentation. The instrumentation--if not a part of the title itself--is indicated, in a general way, directly after the title. Dates are listed following the version information. When applicable, the titles of the movements are listed below. The existence of a sketch (or other version), which does not include one or more of the other movements, is indicated following the title of each movement that is included.
    Many of the sketches of Albright's works were kept separately from the rest of the musical texts, and have been incorporated here into the files of the respective titles. Unidentified sketches and fragments of sketches can be found at the end of the sub-series William Albright Scores.
    - Abiding Passions for Woodwind Quintet (Stage One: Awakening, Stage Two: Ardor, Stage Three: Play by Play, Stage Four: Loss), 1988
      - sketches (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
    - A.G.O. Fight Song, circa 1991
      - lyrics and music (Box 11)
    - An Alleluia Super-Round for Eight or more Singers (similar or mixed voices) and Instruments (optional), 1973
      - reproduction of manuscript and printed score (Box 11)
    - Alliance for Orchestra: A dissertation submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Musical Arts (Music: Composition) in the University of Michigan, 1970
      - annotated reproductions of manuscripts (Box 47)
    - Amerithon: For solo dancer, any number of instruments, tape (optional), film, projections, and revolving masterworks of art, undated
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
      - Amerithon: Suggestions for interpretation of score (instrumental), 1967 (Box 11)
    - Antigone's Reply (Sophocles) for voice and piano, 1987
      - notes (Box 11)
      - sketches (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
      - proofs (Box 11)
      - printed score (Box 11)
    - Bacchanal for Organ Solo and Orchestra, 1981
      - pencil sketch (Box 11)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
      - revision notes (Box 11)
      - printed score (Box 11)
    - Bells in the Air: Concerto for Percussion and Orchestra, undated
      - research (Box 11)
      - notes (Box 11)
      - sketch (Box 55)
    - Bells in the Air for Carillon: A set of six pieces, 1996
      - research (Box 11)
      - notes (Box 11)
      - pencil sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
    - Beulahland Rag, 1967-1969
      - reproduction of manuscript with annotations (Box 11)
      - manuscript on vellum (Box 55)
    - Birthday Canons: for an ensemble of 4 or more instruments and piano obligate, 1980
      - pencil sketch (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 11)
    - The Birth of Jesus/Alleluia for treble voices (SA) and organ with optional mixed choir (SATB) and optional Bells, 1979
      - pencil sketch (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 11)
    - Bolcom's Rag for piano, 1967
      - sketch (Box 11)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
    - Brass Tacks--Ragtime March for two trumpets, horn, and tenor and bass trombone, 1983
      - pencil sketch (Box 11)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
    - Burnt-Fingers (a Characteristic Two-Step) for piano, undated
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
    - [Calgary Organ Concerto] 1998
      - research materials (Box 11)
      - notes (Box 11)
      - sketch (Box 11)
    - Canon in D (Berimbau!) for double bass and harpsichord (or piano), 1984
      - pencil sketch (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 11)
    - Carillon-Bombarde for Organ, 1985
      - pencil sketch (Box 11)
      - manuscript (Box 11)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
    - Caroms for Eight Players, 1966
      - manuscript on vellum (Box 11)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
      - printed transcribed score (Box 11)
    - Chasm for pipe organ (with optional "echo" instrument), 1985
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
      - printed score (Box 11)
      - revision notes (Box 11)
    - Chasm: Symphonic Fragment, 1989
      - sketches (Box 11)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 11)
      - printed score (Box 11)
      - revision notes (Box 11)
    - Chichester Mass: mixed choir a cappella (1. Kyrie, 2. Gloria, 3. Sanctus, 4. Benedictus, 5. Agnus Dei), 1974 revised, 1979
      - sketch fragments (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Kyrie only) (Box 11)
      - photocopied printed score (Box 11)
    - Chorale-Partita in an Old Style on "Wer nur den lieben Gott lasst walten" For Organ, 1963
      - manuscript (Box 12)
      - printed score (Box 12)
    - Chorale-Prelude for Advent: Nun komm der Heiden heiland (Savior of the nations, come!), 1997
      - sketch (Box 12)
      - manuscript (Box 12)
      - printed score [in A New Liturgical Year, John Ferguson, ed. Minneapolis: Augsburg Fortress, 1997] (Box 12)
    - Chorale Prelude for Organ, undated (Box 12)
    - Cod Piece from "Fish Music," 1998
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 55)
    - Concerto for Harpsichord and String Orchestra (1. Largo maestoso; Allegro semplice, 2. Marcia funebre, 3. Incantation and Hoopla), 1991
      - sketch (Box 12)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
      - annotated, printed score (Box 12)
      - annotated, photocopied handwritten parts [removed to Parts] (Box 12)
      - short version--reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - Cortege for voice and piano, undated
      - poem (Box 12)
      - manuscript [incomplete] (Box 12)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - Cross of Gold: music-theater for actors, choir and musicians (1. Overture, 2. Five Oracles of Avarice, 3. Blind Man's Bluff, 4. Motet, 5. Economist's Tale, 6. The Cross of Gold [Game Show]), 1975
      - notes (Box 12)
      - sketch (Five Oracles of Avarice only) (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Box 12)
      - handwritten parts [incomplete] [removed to Parts] (Box 12)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - Cul-de-sac, for solo dancer and any number of instruments (with tape), 1966
      - manuscript (Box 12)
    - Danse Macabre: flute, clarinet, violin, cello, piano, 1971
      - sketch (Box 12)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - David's Songs, for SATB (soloists or chorus) and organ (1. Psalm 149, 1-3, 2. Psalm 116, 1-6, 3. Psalm 137, 1-2, 4. Psalm 150)
      - sketch (Movements 1 and 2 only) (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
      - printed score 1982 (Box 12)
    - Daydream: for 3 keyboard players and sustaining instrument or ensemble, 1975
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - Deo Gratias: arrangement for voice and 5 players, circa 1992
      - notes (Box 12)
      - pencil sketch (Box 12)
      - handwritten parts [incomplete] (Box 12)
      - photocopied parts (Box 12)
    - De Spiritum, organ solo with 2 assistants, 1980
      (Movements: Introduction, I. Unity, II. Celestial Duel, III. Trinity Sonata, IV. Origins, V. Bequeathal, Appendix: The celestial "weave")
      - notes (Box 12)
      - pencil sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - Deum de Deo: A trilogy of pieces for mixed chorus with organ or piano accompaniment, 1988
      (Movements: 1. Jubilate Deo, 2. Deo gratias (soprano solo or SATB), 3. Gloria in excelsis Deo)
      - notes (Box 55)
      - sketch (Movement 1 only) (Box 12)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript [incomplete] (Box 12)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
      - printed score (Box 12)
    - Dirty Eloise for piano (?) and voice (with William Bolcom), 1971
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript with revisions (Box 12)
    - Dona Nobis Pacem, for mixed chorus and piano, 1992
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
      - annotated proofs (Box 12)
    - Doo-Dah, for 3 alto saxophones, 1975
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
    - Dream and Dance, for organ and percussion, 1975
      (Movements: 1. Dream, 2. Dance)
      - manuscript (Box 12)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Movement 1 only) (Box 12)
    - The Dream Rags, for piano, 1970
      (Movements: 1. Sleepwalker's Shuffle, 2. The Nightmare Fantasy Rag (A Night on Rag Mountain), 3. Morning Reveries)
      - manuscript (Box 12)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 12)
      - published score (Box 12)
    - Eleven Short Piano Pieces (Set II), 1962
      - manuscript (Box 13)
    - The Eleventh Hour, 1992
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
    - The Earth is Home (words by Kenneth L. Patton, 1956), 1972
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
    - The Enigma Syncopations, for flute (piccolo), contrabass, percussion (1) and organ
      (Movements: 1. Introduction and Vamp, 2. Torch Song, 3. Stomp)
      - notes (Box 55)
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript 1982 (Box 13)
    - Fantasy-Etudes for Saxophone Quartet 1993
      (Movements: Prelude ("Index"), 1. A Real Nice Number, 2. Pypes, 3. The Fives for Steve, 4. Phantom Galop, 5. Harmonium, 6. They Only Come Out at Night)
      - notes (Box 13)
      - sketches (Box 13)
      - sketches (Box 55)
      - annotated proofs (Box 13)
      - annotated, printed parts (Movement 4 only) (Box 13)
      - printed score (Box 13)
      - Biographical materials for Prism Saxophone Quartet (Box 13)
    - Father, We Thank Thee: A song of thanksgiving for unison choir, soloist or congregation, with piano or organ accompaniment and optional instruments, 1973
      - printed score (Box 13)
    - Five Chromatic Dances for piano solo 1976
      (Movements: 1. Procession and Rounds, 2. Masquerade, 3. Fantasy-mazurka, 4. Hoedown, 5. The Farewell)
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
    - Flights of Fancy: Ballet for Band, 1997
      (Movements: 1. Curtain Raiser, 2. Valse triste, 3. Shimmy, 4. Hymn, 5. Alla marcia: A New Fight Song)
      - manuscript (Box 55)
      - photocopied printed score (Box 13)
      - list of percussion requirements (Box 13)
      - Commission correspondence 1997 (Box 13)
    - Flights of Fancy: Ballet for Organ 1991-1992
      (Movements: 1. Curtain Raiser, for Fred and Louise's Wedding, 2. Valse triste, to the memory of Gretchen Finney, 3. Tango fantastico, for Hector Olivera and Michael Lorimer, 4. Pas de deux, to the memory of Leonard Raver and George Cree, 5. Ragtime Lullaby, to Karen McFarlane on an important birthday [see also Four Dance Tributes], 6. Shimmy, for Philip Brunelle, 7. Hymn, to the memory of my mother, 8. Alla marcia--The AGO Fight Song, to the American Guild of Organists
      [see also AGO Fight Song])
      - notes (Box 13)
      - sketch (Movements 3, 6 and 8 only) (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
    - Flourish for percussion and vibraphone, undated
      - manuscript (Box 13)
    - Foils for Wind and Percussion, 1964
      - manuscript (Box 47)
      - manuscript and reproduction of manuscript parts [Removed to Parts] (Box 47)
    - Foils for Wind Ensemble circa 1964
      (Movements: 1. Quick, 2. Lightly, 3. Moderate, 4. Slow, 5. Fast)
      - annotated, printed score (Box 13)
    - Four Dance Tributes, for piano solo, 1987-1996
      Movements: 1. Stoptime for George, for George Rochberg, 2. A Ragtime Lullaby, for Karen McFarlane, 3. A Post-modern Foxtrot on "Moro lasso" and "Vissi d'arte" for piano left hand [and arm], for Glenn Watkins, 4. Tango fantastico, for Michael Lorimer, Hector Olivera and Waleed Howrani [as arranged for piano by Mr. Howrani]
      [see also Flights of Fancy: Ballet for Organ]
      - sketches (Movements 1 and 2 only) (Box 55)
      - manuscript (Movements 1, 2, and 3 only) (Box 13)
      - reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
    - Four Fancies for harpsichord, 1979
      (Movements: 1. Excentrique, 2. Mirror Bagatelle, 3. Musette, 4. Danza ostinata)
      - notes (Box 55)
      - pencil sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
      - "William Albright's Four Fancies for Harpsichord," by Douglas Reed (Box 13)
    - Frescos: Four Movements for Woodwind Quartet, 1964
      - manuscript (Box 13)
    - Full Moon in March for percussion, chimes, autoharp, dulcimer, organ and tin flutes (play by W.B. Yeats), 1978
      - notes (Box 13)
      - sketch (Box 13)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
      - notes for lecture (Box 13)
    - Gothic Suite for Organ, Strings and Percussion, 1973
      (Movements: 1. Masque, 2. Cakewalk, 3. Tarantella Demente)
      - sketch (Box 55)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 13)
      - annotated, printed organ part (Box 13)
    - Grand Sonata in Rag, 1968
      (Movements: 1. Scott Joplin's Victory, 2. Ragtime Turtledove, 3. Behemoth Two-Step)
      - sketches (Movements 2 and 3 only) (Box 14)
      - manuscript (Box 14)
      - annotated reproduction of manuscript (Box 14)
      - printed score with recording notes (Box 14)